Friends with Brews!
Uh, Peter.
You can start talking anytime.
Well, I was waiting for my introduction.
Oh, well I said Peter, that's the introduction you-
That's all I get these days. Well, I guess that's better than nothing.
It may not be the intro you want, but it's the intro you're gonna get.
Yeah, it's the intro that I need or that I deserve or something like that.
Yes.
Hey, it has been a beat, so to speak, since you and I have recorded.
It's been a hot minute. But you did get a couple of amazing stand-ins for me while I was gone,
including the legendary John Chidgey. Right, but there was a peter sandwich. You were stuck in the
middle there, because when you came back... Yeah, I know you talked about the peter sandwich and
my light brown roast and all those other things while I was gone. Yes, I caught all that. Thank
you. Wow, wow. I sense a bitterness from someone. Well, I was drinking a lot of bitter coffee down
in Costa Rica, so you know. Yeah, I actually recorded both of those while you were gone,
and the middle one with you after you came back, of course. If anybody listens, that'll be obvious.
But then, because the timing was very close on the one that I did with you and the one I
did with Clay, I went ahead and edited the one with you first. Excellent. Well,
shall we introduce our brews for the evening? I think so. I think so. Let us talk about yours
first. Very well. Mine is a new one. I have not had it before. I just picked up a four-pack of
this today. I was at the local Wegmans from probably my favorite brewery, Ommegang Brewery
up in Cooperstown, New York. This is the triple-fruited triple. So, it's triply-fruited
tripele. Limited release, orange, peach, mango, Belgian style triple ale with natural flavors.
Okay, I can't I don't I don't can you say all that again all that again? Yeah. Yeah
I just did say it all again. Oh the beer. Yes. Ommegang brewery
triple fruited trippelle
limited release
orange
peach mango belgian style triple ale with natural flavors and it's a mere
9.0% alcohol I have not had
a beer this strong for some time and I haven't had a beer this strong on the
podcast for quite some time mm-hmm so I just popped the that was probably a less
than impressive I don't know I heard it pretty good I don't know what you're
recording got well hopefully it's the same because they're both coming through
the same theoretically coming through the same microphone but it's very
important okay the poor well I did I did double check before I started recording
So I trust you that doesn't mean what I wouldn't I mean about to drink beer
It looks good. That's good a nice
Okay, it's getting darker
Your lights are shifting in and out. Yeah, that's pretty blonde looking
Yeah, well, it's it's a you know, it's a fruity. It's a triple style. So it's not not as strong as a quadruple
but I mean it's
Nine percent. I mean once you once you get over eight percent, I don't think it really matters much
Alright, well I have two brews. One is a Coava coffee again, and this one is called Nao Valle.
I don't know how it's pronounced, but it's N-A-Y-O-V-A-L-L-E.
And it is... Oh, now I gotta go back to the link. Oh my god, I'm messing everything up here.
Sorry. Sometimes having Rectangle Pro can be disconcerting.
Okay, it's from Guatemala. It says rich chocolatey and yeah, just rich chocolatey.
It says well-rounded notes of orange, almond butter and milk chocolate in the cup. Okay.
Okay.
That's number one. Here's my get drunk quick kit.
Get drunk kit. Got it. But you're starting with a coffee and then you're moving on to
the get drunk afterwards or? No, I have both at the same time, you dummy.
Oh, call me dummy dummy. I don't know what you're doing.
Okay, my second one is Cascade Lakes Brewing Salted Caramel Porter.
Interesting.
I was looking at something very similar to that today, but I resisted the urge.
I bought one new beer and that's the one that I have now.
And I would love to tell you what percent it is because you're all about the percent.
It's an important number.
Oh my God.
Not to these guys.
Oh wait, 5.8.
This is a lightweight.
Oh, so you can just pound that.
Yeah, I can.
I've got, I can drink the whole six pack.
I heard that.
Yeah, I'm sorry I didn't do it near the mic,
but here goes.
Probably can't hear that.
I can't even hear it.
(water dripping)
I can hear that.
Okay.
Oh yeah.
And it's brown as you would expect.
Yep, I would expect.
Did you go to Powell's Books while we were here?
While you were here?
You took me there the first time.
While we were here.
Not the second time.
Peter, when I lived here.
When I was there, yes.
The first time that I visited, yes.
Alright, are we ready? Are we toasting? Are we drinking yet?
Yeah, let's toast.
I want to drink. Let's go.
Kanpai my buddy.
Dry up that cup.
Okay, now earlier you were telling me in messages that you desperately needed a beer.
You were sounding really elky. I mean you were-
Had a day.
Pleading for alcohol. Okay, but here's the thing.
A person who is close to you, whose name I won't mention because I honestly can't recall,
just had tooth surgery, dental surgery, major invasive ripping of bone out of other bone,
and here you are whining about how much you need a beer and having a plate installed too a metal
plate oh my god oh wow what happened to her i have no idea i swear it wasn't my fault your honor
okay i was gonna ask i'm just gonna get mighty suspicious here that sounds horrible yeah yeah
so that was the first i heard of it was yesterday and you know it's like i need dental surgery i'm
like why don't you come and chill at my place while you recover from that so yeah so she's
doing that. That's a major thing. Yep, so she's doing that and we're drinking beer. She can't
drink beer right now. She's post-novacaine, post-anesthesia, and on lots of Tylenol. So
more beer for me. Right, but who's going to stop her? Let's put it that way. Well, she's not a huge
beer drinker. But I gotta say, this is love at first sip. This is good. Oh. Yes, this triple is
very nice. Hey, why is everything that's super amazing a limited release? I mean, you would hope
that limited releases are going to be super amazing. That's good. But then some of my
favorite ones are like either seasonal and then they never come back again or they're
limited release and it just chaps my hide. So all I can think is, it's got to be something
to do with marketing rather than supply and demand. And all I can think of is back when
my parents owned restaurants, I remember one of the things that was, you know, they would
They would always run specials, right?
So there's your regular menu.
And then here are the specials.
My father's Greek spinach pie,
spanakopita, was always on the special.
Wow.
It never was on the regular menu.
You could always get it.
There was never a day it wasn't available.
It was always on the special.
And someone asked once and my mom said,
"No, as soon as you take it off the specials,
it doesn't sell anymore."
Wow, you never told me.
I never saw this side of your parents before.
I didn't know about your dad's Greek spinach pie.
The only thing I know about your dad is that he thinks his email is stored in the computer.
Right, he doesn't know how to use technology, exactly.
You've been holding out on me!
You've been purposely trying to give me a really dark view of your parents.
Yep, I did.
I left out the spinach pie all these years.
Yes.
Oh my god.
Wow.
That should have been week one, dude.
That would have been great, the first email.
I'm listening to, I'm listening to dual boot radio.
Yeah.
Your first listener.
My dad makes excellent spinach pie.
Exactly.
My name is Peter.
Long short time listener of the show.
Just thought you should know my father makes excellent spinach pie to which you doubtlessly
would have responded somehow.
I don't remember who your, who your cohost was at that one.
That was Derek Fitzgerald, I think Derek, right.
You would have said Derek, I think he's hitting on you.
Yeah.
That's what you would have said.
By the way, I haven't talked to Derek in years and years and years. And I got a message from him on
LinkedIn recently and he said, "Call me back as soon as you can." And I said, "Okay." And then
it's been like three weeks and I haven't done it yet. I need to get a hold of him.
[Laughter]
Now, I forget, was he a Monolith 2000?
He is a Monolith 3000.
Is?
Yeah. He still is.
He was and is. So you guys have both been there for a while.
Got it.
Yeah. He started like, I don't know, a year and a half,
maybe a couple of years after me. And then anyway,
he's in California at this point in his life. He's been there for many, many,
many, many years.
Well, I, I guess we need a code name for,
for my largest engagement because I don't have one
for it. We need one. I have my largest engagement, but I don't have a code word.
Like I need a monolith 3000.
Okay. Yeah. For a minute I was not understanding that this was still work
related and I was like, my head was spinning.
This is still working. Well, how much beer have you had?
And then you said engagement and I was like, Oh my God.
Oh my God. Peter's engaged to more than one? Oh my God.
Peter's engaged to the beer he's drinking.
So maybe we should put that out as a, you know, that should be a challenge to the listeners.
Just put that out as a competition. Who can name Peter's like...
But wouldn't it help? Here's the problem though. They don't know what it is.
Right. But I was going to say, here are the parameters. Here are the parameters. So it's
It's a large healthcare provider.
I like to say, you know, it moves at the speed of a, well, it turns at the speed of a battleship.
I would like to say that it has had intimate relations with the Chinese, not of its own
initiation.
I don't think so.
I think I've managed to keep that distance, keep that at arm's length.
Yeah.
You've installed the proverbial steel network underwear?
We've done a full metal long John's with them. Yeah.
So, uh, yeah, no,
I'm not going to admit to any close intimate connections with the chair, with,
with, with APT, with them. Sorry.
Oh my God. Next thing you know,
last pass will be admitting that they were screwed up. The was it?
Oh my goodness. I was going to say, have you been following that? Of course.
I know you have been following.
It just gets worse and worse and worse and worse.
I, you know, so yes, I did resist until just a few months ago.
I was like, look, everyone gets breached.
Everyone. Okay. Well, yeah, it happens once or twice or three times.
Okay. But it's how you handle, Oh, they have, okay.
They've been mishandling these for, Oh, okay. Okay. Okay. So yeah.
But I have at your advice and that of some of others, but primarily you,
I have switched to 1Password.
Not only does the company have a better security track record, the app just works better than
LastPass on like all platforms.
Yeah. This is one of those things where I can tell you, but you're not really going
to know that. You're just going to think it's my preference.
Well, but the thing is like I had no baseline and I thought LastPass in general was pretty
good, but some of the, there was some shortcomings on the desktop side, but 1Password, and
And of course, now that the beer is starting to kick in, I can't tell you what these are.
But 1Password has polished a couple of these edges off of LastPass that were just a little
bit rough.
And it's great.
Yeah.
And the other thing about 1Password is they have a website which has a...
Well, first of all, they blog extensively.
They also have a community forum where you can ask questions and stuff.
And they're pretty open.
You know, they don't have their source code there, but they're pretty open about their
philosophy about security and how they do things.
I mean, you can get enough answers from them to feel comfortable that at least these guys
are really taking it seriously. So here's the thing. I got hooked on LastPass years ago before
they were purchased by LogMeIn. And I remember they had an interview with the developer at the
time, the lead developer. I don't even know if he's still associated with them anymore. And he was,
I believe he was interviewed on Security Now. And I remember that, you know, Steve Gibson did this
big review of this deep dive of the architecture, because there's a lot of questions like, you
know, why should I trust my passwords to a cloud vault? And they had all the right answers.
And I remember being really impressed by the answers back then.
That's the thing. That's why I say, even with 1Password, even though nothing has happened
with them to date, even though I believe in the team and I like the communications that
they give, I'm not going to stand here and say, nothing's ever going to happen to them,
know, because I can't. That's impossible to say. Right. I have an open mind about it.
Yeah, no security. You have to look backwards. It's like, it's just like Steve Ballmer when
he was at, you know, like Windows XP is, is going to be the most secure operating system
ever. Developers, developers, developers, developers, developers. Doesn't he own a sports
team now? Didn't they shuffle him off to own a sports team? He's like a sports team owner
in Seattle and I can't remember which one he owns. I wanted to say, isn't he dead? But
No, that was the other co-founder of Microsoft.
Oh my God.
No, he's the guy that owned the...
He was a part owner in a Portland Trailblazers
or something like that.
Paul Allen.
Paul Allen, thank you.
He was one I was thinking of, yes.
I'm only at 5.8%, so I'm okay.
I can remember Paul Allen.
I'm 9% and I'm feeling every one of them.
Oh, hey, what was your exercise today?
Today, I just did a light yoga class.
So today is supposed to be a cross-training day
or maybe jogging 20 or 30 minutes a day.
Oh, that's not gonna happen.
Yeah, I taught a yin yang hybrid yoga class.
So that was fun.
When I was, so, okay, I'll get into this topic in a minute
but as I was generating a transcript for episode one,
we were talking about different types of yoga
and you were explaining to me some of the origins
of some of them and then we were talking
about the evil bastardly men.
But one of the things you were talking about was hot yoga
I was like gonna ask you have you been back to hot yoga?
Yeah, have you been naked in the street again since we last talked about yoga Peter?
Thank you for asking the yeah, I know yeah, thank you have I stopped beating my wife right got it. Oh
Brother no, I have not been naked in the street again
Since you asked about it, okay
Why was it the poor reviews last time
It was cold outside. We've gone through a cold snap here in New England.
What show was that? I was swimming. Oh, that was Seinfeld. That's right.
Oh, I was in the pool.
Yeah, I was in the pool.
It was Shrinkage. Shrinkage. That's what it was.
Okay, so since I vaguely hinted at it, I want to announce that the thing that I kept saying
I was working on, which is transcripts for Friends with Brews, is now active.
Are you whispering these transcripts?
No, yes, I'm whispering them.
And so, basically any episode that has a transcript currently available,
you will see it when you're looking at the episode page,
and next to the date and the running time, there will be a little transcript link.
And right now, the only ones that have transcripts,
also on the front page, underneath the intro paragraph,
there's an episodes link, there's a transcripts link, and there's an RSS subscribe link.
But there's only three transcripts right now, because I've only generated them for three episodes.
Episode 1, which is why I remembered the hot yoga thing.
Episode 22, which was the year of the megapickle.
And Episode 26, which was the current live episode, which is the one with clay.
And the reason why I only have three so far is even though...
So here's the...
Should I go into the details?
Yeah, so I'm using whisper.cpp, which does a really good job of generating them.
But sometimes, based on when things are said,
It'll have stuff in the same paragraph that might be from part of it from me, part of it from you.
And in order to clean that up, it takes some time. And the other thing is, I think it was actually
better when I was just outputting the raw text only. But at John Chidgey's recommendation,
or suggestion, or question, I'm also at the same time now outputting an .srt file, which means that
I can embed the SRT in the RSS feed and players that can take advantage of it will show
the transcript as the words are at the appropriate times as those words are being said. And I'm not
cleaning that one up quite as much. I'm, you know, doing regexes for like our names and a few other
things, but those are time-based so I don't really need to clean those up because the words happen
when they happen. But the ones that are just a raw text file, I'm trying to separate them out
into paragraphs based on who's talking at the time. I'm not putting names on them.
I'm not going to all that amount of time, but it still takes a pretty good amount of time per
episode. So even when I get caught up, which is going to take a long, long time, I don't think
that transcripts will be available for brand new episodes right away. It's going to be a few days,
maybe. Do you think...
Do I think? Out of all of our listeners, how many do you think are gonna care?
Oh, if they're available right away? Yeah. No, no one.
I ask this in all seriousness because there is a podcast that I listen to pretty much every day.
I listen to, usually every morning, I'll listen to like three, sometimes four newscasts.
Is that the Hot Yoga podcast? No. That is not news.
I'll listen to like three or four news podcasts and one of them includes show notes and links
to all the articles that they cover.
Well, most of them usually do.
One of them routinely releases them like several hours after the episode.
So I listen to the episode like depends, you know, like usually I'll try to get up and
meditate for a little bit before, but sometimes I'm like straight out of bed and I'm really
curious and I, Oh, that's an interesting headline. And I get sucked in and I
start playing it. And then I'm like, Oh, that sounds really interesting. I need
to read in, you know, dig into this deeper. And I look and they haven't
published show notes yet. It's still yesterday's show notes. So I can't, you
know, like find the article or I have to like, Oh my God, so much work. I have to
start doing my own research and Googling for this. So I was just curious though,
because I am, you know, a use case, an example here where like, yeah,
I would like to have this right now. By the time I hear the episode,
I would like to have show notes available, for example.
No, the show notes will be available right now, just like they always are.
For every episode, the show notes will be available as soon as I publish it.
It's part of the publishing process.
The only thing that won't be available immediately is the raw text transcript.
Right, right. And I got that. I understand there's a difference,
but there's also a parallel where I'm saying it's very similar to there's something that's combing along with the episode
Eventually is anyone gonna care?
Hey, I don't think so and be if they do they can let me know
But here's the other thing is I don't want to delay an episode just for the transcript
So even if they let me know that I'll probably say I'll do the best I can that'll probably be my answer
Because having transcripts is a hundred percent better than what we had before with respect to transcripts was nothing
Here's what I'm gonna do. I am going to
offer I'm out of the generosity and the kindness of my heart and
My financial well-being I will refund
100% of all of our subscribers dollars to any subscriber who complains about
Not having the transcripts available at release time
when the shows drop. How's that sound? Peter you're gonna bankrupt us. No no no
I'm paying out of it now I'm gonna back from you I'll do it just myself. Me and
the mighty financial backing of Paradigm Consulting Company LLC we will we will
back all of that. This is almost like poor Tesla having to cover the expenses
for the car that crashed when the steering wheel came off. Well steering
wheels really should be optional in a driverless car don't you think? Well it
turns out that having the steering wheel held on to the column by nothing more
than friction doesn't always work depending on how the driver you know
interacts with the steering wheel. Sounds like a Lego set I used to have when I
was a kid. Uh-huh except it wasn't made by your Lego set wasn't made by an a**hole.
Well thank you because I'm the one who assembled it. You didn't create the
Lego themselves. But I assembled it. You didn't pour plastic into little you know
what do you what do you call those die when you pour them into a shape when you
Yeah, that's a die.
That's a die.
Yep.
Die cast Legos, man.
Die Elon, die!
Oh wait, sorry.
Too much?
All right, what else do we have?
We didn't actually have pre-approved show notes this time, did we?
No, I did.
So here's the thing.
Where?
I looked.
I went to Google Docs and I looked and I saw nothing.
Oh, did it not put them in the...
I don't know.
Oh, there's friends with pros.
I see that.
Here, see if you can follow that link.
Now I see it.
Yep, yep, now I see it.
Nino was right.
That's the current name. It can change.
Nina. Who's Nina?
This is referring to the balloons. Remember the 99 balloons or the left balloons or whatever it is?
Nina.
Six ninety-niners, left balloons. Yeah, I got it.
Right.
Yeah. Right.
Anyway, that was when I wanted to talk about the balloons, but that's old news now.
Oh, those balloons. Yes. Yes. I get it. I got it. Okay. Okay. So Apple reportedly...
I'm just reading these short.
I know.
Apple reportedly working on touch screen mags followed by why Apple will never
ever create a touch screen mag.
Right. Well, that was an article from 2020. So here's the reason why I put these two links
in here was because what I don't understand, Peter, you and I are multi-platform users.
We use Linux, although I don't have a Linux computer in my house right now.
I certainly have Linux servers. We use Windows both, you know, because we use Windows for work.
Have to. Right.
Let's be honest. Let's be honest.
Because we have to.
And well, part of my job is interesting with Windows because we use Windows Server
for everything, including the operation of our semiconductor test equipment.
Basically, we use servers in the place that you would.
It's weird. We use Windows servers.
And technically, I guess they are serving.
It's just that there's so much communication going on between everything
that you couldn't do it with a client version of Windows.
It has to be a server version.
So anyway, we help administer those servers, we install those servers, we image those servers,
we you know, I apply the security patches to those servers, all these different things.
So it is kind of interesting actually, but and then we use Macs at home.
Right.
And so I guess maybe I've been eased into the idea of touch screens.
Like the whole Apple thing has always been, oh, no one will use a touch screen on a laptop.
It's ergonomically incorrect.
You'll break your shoulder if you're reaching out to touch your screen all the time.
First of all, no one uses touch screens like that.
You use them intermittently.
Occasionally you'll touch something on the screen.
They're great for scrolling, all kinds of stuff like that.
And what I don't understand, Mac people cannot get it through their heads.
Just because Apple at one point said nobody wants a touch screen vertical surface.
But look at the iPad Pro.
It sits on a keyboard.
And until the trackpad keyboard came along, the only keyboard they sold didn't have anything
on it for touching. So that meant that you could only use it by reaching up and touching
the iPad screen, which is now basically vertical. Exactly the same as a laptop with a touchscreen,
not a bit of difference, Peter.
But so click. So isn't part of this though, like part of the culture of Apple where, you
know, someone decreed some time ago, we will not do that. Right. We will never have a video
There's no need for it. Therefore it will never happen and it's Apple just has this reluctance
to advance
No, no
No
It's not just Apple being reluctant to advance because Steve Jobs said there was never gonna be a video iPod like the year before there
Was a video iPod they say whatever works for that was okay
I was gonna say that's just flat-out a lie because there's no way they that Apple would have rushed a video iPod to market within
one year. Now Apple's laptops also do have the best screens. Like my MacBook Pro has got one of
the best screens on any laptop anywhere. It's beautiful. Yep. Maybe they couldn't make the
screens quite as thin or maybe they couldn't make them quite as good looking with touch. I don't
know. I'm not saying that that's true. I'm saying who knows? Right. If that's the case, then okay,
I'm okay with them erring on the side of not putting in a touchscreen. But aside from that,
there is no reason not to have one. If you don't want to touch it, don't friggin touch it. It's
It's that simple. 99.9% of the time I don't touch my PC laptop screen.
But every now and then I do. And guess what? Having it be a touchscreen
doesn't kill me at all. It's not so much about Apple. It's Apple users.
Apple users are the biggest status quo people in the universe. They think whatever currently
is is dogma. Oh my God, you can't change. That is the way it has to be.
Mm-hmm. No, it isn't. It's just the way it is right now
Click
Anyway, what are your thoughts since you're not an a$$--le? What are your thoughts on?
Do you care at all about touch screens on Mac?
How much do you use your touchscreen on your PC?
Like are you waiting anxiously for a touchscreen on your Mac at present the only touchscreen I own
The only ones are my iPhone and my Apple watch. Okay, but when you had a PC presumably
I had Microsoft Surface and a Microsoft Surface Book and I you never had a Windows laptop that had a touchscreen
Surface Book surface book was a laptop. What is that? It was a laptop that could it's the Microsoft Surface with a keyboard
It's basically a laptop with a detachable screen
Interesting. So yes
It is a laptop with a touchscreen
The surface is a tablet for which you can buy a case that does as a keyboard the surface book is
The same exact thing but it comes with said keyboard as a unit and it detaches and it's a little bigger
Other than that, it's like 99% identical
But what I'm talking about is most Windows laptops have touch screens and I mean regular laptops where it is a full laptop
It is always a laptop nothing detaches
now the only ones that I've ever had on the Windows side were surfaces surface or surface book and
as you know, like the really the biggest thing I use those for is occasionally drawing something or
Putting my signature on a document
Yeah
and
That's literally the biggest thing or sometimes marking up something when I want to like just circle something and say here
And I don't want to make it look like a second grader did it with a crayon?
Because that's what it looks like when you use a touchpad or a mouse to try to draw something
Interacting with your chat GPT robot lover. No, I do that, but the keyboard. Thank you
So
Anyway, but would it bother you if they came out with a touchscreen Mac? Would you be like all open arms? No, honestly
Here's the thing and here's that this might be a marketing thing though. I probably would not buy another iPad anytime soon
because
Right now my iPad I do miss it occasionally
But I gave it to my mom and hopefully you know in the nursing home
They'll use it with her to start drawing so she can start communicating better, right?
But other than that I would use my iPad as a secondary display to my Mac or to sign documents
Or you know to consume media or read email and stuff, but there's nothing other than signing documents
There's nothing I can't do on my iPad
There's some nothing that I can do on my iPad that I can't do on my laptop
Right? I can do everything I can do on the iPad with my laptop other than easily use a nice big fat touchscreen
Now that I have a mobile Mac again
I have a laptop Mac and I do everything on my Mac now that I used to do on my iPad Pro
But the iPad that I'm using even though it's far from the best iPad because I gave those to my family members
It still makes a hell of a good book reader. You will never get that on a laptop
I would never use a laptop for that
It also does make way better of a video watcher
Like not having that keyboard and that hinge there. It's so much better now
If you're gonna prop it up on the bed and not hold it. You may as well use a lot of that in
General if I'm in bed, I follow a rule that the only thing I'm going to do
besides
If it involves a screen
It involves a screen of some sort I'm gonna be reading a book and frankly for those I usually will use a Kindle
I'll use use an Amazon Kindle or a physical book right right I have a just a few books in iBooks
You know I've thrown a lot of PDFs in there, but in general if I'm gonna just sit
You know usually by the time I get to bed. I'm tired so if I'm gonna be reading something
It's not gonna be more than a few minutes, and I'm gonna get tired and just fall asleep
Then you're gonna wake up later with that thing face down in the bed my face
Yeah, that's why you don't want an iPad Pro then yeah, I would hurt yeah, oh man
Are you kidding especially the the full-on, you know full-size 12-inch? Yeah, so I don't have a Kindle
And I have used the Kindle app on the iPad in the past and I gotta say I don't like it at all
I'm sure the Kindle itself is a much better much better experience
But the Kindle app sucks so bad that I just do everything in books books
Apple Books is so much of a better app
So the reason that I use the Kindle app is I do have a number of things that I purchased on the Amazon store
Right, so that comes there. Sure. I
Do like the Kindle the Kindle I have like I think it's an eighth generation Kindle
It's smaller than an iPad mini but bigger than an iPhone
Pro max just for comparison, which is perfect size for reading. Yeah decent size
I like the fact that you know
I don't have to charge it for weeks at a time so I can just forget about it and still works because it's got the
Sony E Ink as opposed to a you know, a backlit display
And also it's pretty
Dumb, you know as an application or you know, it pretty much only does one thing
It reads me my you know shows me my content so I can't nice. Oh, I'll just check email
Oh, I'll surf the web a little bit, you know, so when I want to focus on just reading it's nice
My problem when I start reading is I don't
Go online so much as I switch over to my crossword puzzle app and I switch between my book and my crossword puzzle
okay, and then
Then half the night will be over and I'll realize that I've made I've read five pages of book
but I've done a bunch of crossword puzzles. And that's not bad. I mean, it's a good way to spend
the time, but it does, it is a deviation from the reading that I was planning on doing.
Right. Yeah, I get that.
It's still not as bad as bouncing onto Mastodon and scrolling through what other people are saying for
five hours and then realizing, you know, oh, you know, which-
Indeed.
I admit, I like cat videos and I like some of the cute animal videos. And so sometimes I'll spend
time on reddit looking at those instead of reddit's a hellhole you have to be careful but oh hell yeah
now my time reading stuff like that i just noticed too sometime along the way somehow apparently i
enabled notifications on the reddit app on my phone my god which also implies that at some point
along the way i installed the reddit app on my phone oh my god why i i got unclear so anyway
Speaking of displays though and touch screens. Let's stay on that loop. I
recently purchased a high definition
32 inch display on my desktop. Oh, what do you mean by high definition? Are we talking 5k? 4k?
That's not high definition.
I mean, I know it is compared to the other one now if you look in the recording if you were looking at the video
If you see back there, yeah, that's a standard definition
ultra wide monitor. That back there is essentially like two 24 inch monitors bolted together.
See, that sucks because you could see every pixel on something that big.
Well, I bought it almost three years ago. Okay.
No, I understand that, but I was going to send you a link. There's a 5K competitor.
There's a good 5K competitor to the studio display that I'm using that recently came out that would
be a wonderful pair with your Mac. You should have waited.
And how much does that cost?
Well, a lot less than the studio. Well, I say a lot less. I don't know. I'll find the details for you.
Okay, so I bought the one from Monoprice and the reason is it was reviewed in Wired. They're like,
"We love this display." I'm like, "Okay, let's see what they do." It was 300 and some odd dollars.
It was 300 mumble dollars. I honestly don't remember exactly how many it was.
And it's pretty darn good. It's not great. There are times if I have a lot of dark
dark colors rendering on the screen, I see some flickering and I saw I did a little
bit of digging to see like you know, some people said check your cable. So, I did swap
out the cable and it comes back but it comes back so infrequently that I might not care.
What's the refresh rate on this thing?
60, 60 hertz or 50 if you want to dumb it down.
Don't do that.
But just having a high def super big giant monitor, like this is awesome.
I had that ultra wide, again for the last, I bought that shortly after I returned to
work for Healthcare 3000.
And I thought it was great except the vertical refresh, the vertical resolution was no better
than any of my other monitors.
So like anything vertical, it's like scroll city.
So I really hated that.
here, like I can comfortably have a couple of spreadsheets, a video, email, another web
browser, a terminal, all on the screen at the same time in nice high resolution and
not feel cramped at all. So this is, this is nice.
Yeah, see, I'm so used to 5k. I don't know if I could go down to four again. Now those
two monitors behind me, those are my work, my home work monitors, my at home, but for
monitors that I plug my PC into those are 1280 or whatever a standard your
homework monitors my homework yeah I do my homework on this but those are 1280
or whatever you know now at work see this is the weird thing
model of 3000 nobody has actual 4k monitors there there's a couple people
and I wonder where they got them but like there are software developers that
have been there a long time but everybody else has 1280 monitors now I
managed to get my boss to buy me what are they called UHD they're in between
4k and HD monitors I think ultra-high ultra-high high def yeah so I have two
of those on my desk at work and they look a hell of a lot better than these
okay but there's still nothing like a 5k or even a 4k so we can put it into the
show notes I'll message you this but I bought the mono price 32 inch crystal
Pro monitor 4k UHD 60 Hertz 65 watts USB-C height adjustable stand VA and the
product number is 43020 which is funny because when I look for my speakers when
I want to change my sound output it's 43020 so it's referred to by its product
number all through the documentation and through my system settings which I think
kind of funny. Oh you know what I think I think QHD is what those work ones are. QHD, yeah. QHD.
2560 by 1440. Okay. So those are QHD. UHD is 4k right? Ultra HD? Yeah that's what I have. I have
4HD. Yeah I have I have 4k UHD. That's what I have. Yes and mine are my the one I have at work
is sometimes called 2k monitors. Which is nothing, right? Well, it's better than the
1280 ones that I have back here that I used to have at work that I brought home once I got the
better ones. So one of the podcasts that I listen to, so I've recently been unsubscribing from a
number of or unfollowing a number of podcasts. Don't say that. They're going to unfollow us now.
No, not ours. You can't unfollow ours. That's not allowed. Okay, gotcha. Just because I'm like,
look, it's been months I have not listened to an episode or in some cases, like I've realized I
went back and I was like, I haven't listened to any of these. I'm going to unsubscribe. Oh,
they stopped releasing episodes like eight months ago. Oh, okay. Well, there you go. Great. There's
a reason I don't listen anymore. Yeah. There's a reason. Right. They unlistened to me. Yeah.
Right. One of them that I still love though, and my favorite running podcast, cause I still
subscribe to a number of running podcasts. My favorite one is called Trail Runner Nation.
And they have a number of rotating hosts in addition to guests on the show. And one of them
is the guys AJW are his initials. I forget his name, but he just released his own podcast. He's
started his own podcast now. And the rule is they talk about running and they have a drink and it's
usually a beer, but his rule is they, the podcast show, the length of the episode will be as long as
his drink lasts. Oh. And I kind of like that, but I must warn you, I am down to my last sip of my
beer, which means we either need to wrap this or I need to get another drink. Um, I would prefer that
you get another drink because my god, Peter, we've only been going for, oh well, it's been 42 minutes.
Uh, it's up to you. It's up to you. You only, you know what you have in your future. I just finished
11.2 ounces of 9% Belgian triple and I can barely stand up.
Yeah, but the, I think I would, this is just me, but I would think that the person downstairs
in immense pain who you're helping take care of right now really would benefit and probably
want you to just be so drunk that you can't even get down the stairs. I would think.
I was thinking you would say would want me to go spend time with her to make sure she's okay
Maybe even help cook dinner or something. I don't know that's just stupid
No, we can wrap it up I totally agree with you I don't want you to get any I think it's it's probably the smart thing
To do let's just put it that way. I mean literally my lips are numb
They look numb
That's how good you're Wow. Oh my god, Peter. Just yeah, I was to you dear listener
that was not to Scott. Scott might have intercepted it.
[laughter]
Peter just kissed his own snowball.
No, I kissed you, dear listener. Just you.
Yeah. I don't know how to bring it back up to end on a positive—
[laughter]
You don't know how to follow—I think we should just wrap it up and tell folks how to find us.
Here's where we gotta move on.
At a certain point, we gotta move on. I think this is that point.
You can find us at friendswithbrews.com. You can find us on the Mastodon at some
link or other from friendswithbrews.com. I bet I could find it if I looked.
It is a little harder to tell folks how to find us on Mastodon than it is on Twitter,
but it's worth it.
appdot.net/@friendswbrews. Or just search @friendswbrews from whatever site you're
on on Mastodon and you'll find us. Yeah, what about you individually?
Oh, I'm appdot.net@scottaw.
Wow.
Or @scottaw@appdot.net. If you want to...
Anyway, whatever.
That's weird. See, I'm at nikolaidis@infosec.exchange.
Uh huh. You are at infosec.exchange. You've been exchanging infosecs with people. Wow, that came out wrong.
Anyway, if you go, if you go to a Friends with Brews.com/friends, you will find our Mastodon links.
So, wow.
Yeah, that was a, wow.
Yeah, that was a, that was a rumor I just started right there, Peter.
Wow.
Okay.
Talk about your big red button.
No, I'm not going to talk about it.
I'm just going to push it.
Big red button.